# **DILLON ABBOTT**

## **Full Stack Developer**

dragonhunter1230@proto n.me

+1 (713)730-6590

Houston, TX

LinkedIn

**Github** 

I am an innovative and passionate Full Stack developer with 6 years of experience building and maintaining responsive web applications using modern web frontend and backend technology stack and cloud services to make the project another level and meaningful contributions to teams of varying sizes and scopes.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Bancor** - Front End Developer

January 2018 - June 2021

New York, NY

- Worked on the Payments team to save over 50,000 customers time and improve cash flow through the development of modern, responsive customer experiences
- Led the migration from AWS to GCP for the team to reduce loud costs by \$260,000 per year
- Worked closely with the product team to re-configure the projessing of invoices, saving customers over 125,000 manual hours of work per month
- Mentored 3 junior front end developers on the team on leact and documentation best practices within the organization

## Pitstop - Frontend Web Develope

August 2016 - November 2017

New York, NY

- ry to create reusable components that saved over 200 hours of development time per Contributed to the in-house UI libr month
- re elivery management platform with 100+ business customers to create, manage, and Created a web app MVP for a § monitor deliveries using React and Redux
- Added new features to a medication app with 5,000+ monthly active users to enable the uploading of audio and video content using React and Redux
- Through A/B testing of different components and combinations improved customer conversion rate by 17%, representing \$500,000+ in incremental annual revenue

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Delaware - Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

2012 - 2017

### **SKILLS**

- Python (Django)
- SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL)
- Cloud (GCP, AWS)
- JavaScript (ES6, React, Redux, Node.js)
- Typescript
- HTML/CSS
- CI/CD

Newark, DE